John A. Lomax and Alan Lomax papers
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series I: Correspondence, 1925-1952 and undated
  - Subseries III: Alan Lomax, 1935-1969 and undated (Box-folder 3/115)
    - October 1941 (Box-folder 6/175)
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1941-10-17
      - Alan Lomax to Fletcher Collins, Jr., 1941-10-17
      - Alan Lomax to Laura Boulton, 1941-10-21
      - Alan Lomax to Moses Smith, 1941-10-21
      - Harold Spivacke to Ruby Pickens Tartt, 1941-10-21
      - Alan Lomax to Harry Partch, 1941-10-24
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1941-10-24
      - Alan Lomax to Onah Spencer, 1941-10-24
      - Alan Lomax to Mary Waller Bonelli, 1941-10-25
      - Alan Lomax to Lawrence W. Chappell, 1941-10-25
      - Anne Schley Duggan to John A. Lomax, 1941-10-25
      - Moses Smith to Alan Lomax, 1941-10-27
      - Charles S. Johnson to Harold Spivacke, 1941-10-27
      - Charles Seeger to Alan Lomax, 1941-10-30
    - November 1941 (Box-folder 6/176)
      - Ruby Pickens Tartt to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-03
        proposed John A. Lomax/Tartt 1941 Southern recording trip
      - Alan Lomax to Fletcher Collins, Jr., 1941-11-04
      - Frances M. Foster to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-04
      - Alan Lomax to Harry Partch, 1941-11-05
      - Harry Partch to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-05
      - Ruby Pickens Tartt to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-05
      - Alan Lomax to Marie Prince, 1941-11-06
      - Alan Lomax to Moses Smith, 1941-11-06
      - Alan Lomax to Jerome B. Wiesner, 1941-11-07
      - Alan Lomax to Ruby Pickens Tartt, 1941-11-07
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1941-11-08
      - Roger Butterfield to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-08
        Life magazine
      - Fletcher Collins, Jr. to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-08
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1941-11-08
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1941-11-10
      - Ronald F. Lee to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-10
        U.S. Department of the Interior
      - Charles B. Seton to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-10
      - T.J. Brandon to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-11
      - Lawrence W. Chappell to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-11
      - Fletcher Collins, Jr. to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-11
      - Alan Lomax to T.J. Brandon, 1941-11-13
      - Alan Lomax to Hazel L. Muller, 1941-11-13
      - Alan Lomax to Roger Butterfield, 1941-11-15
      - Alan Lomax to Josephine Schwartz, 1941-11-18
      - Mary Jo Wallace to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-21
      - Management Corporation of America to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-21
      - Dorothy Kammerer to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-21
      - Alan Lomax to Fletcher Collins, Jr., 1941-11-22
      - T.J. Brandon to John A. Lomax, 1941-11-26
      - Charles E. Griffith to Alan Lomax, 1941-11-26
      - Alan Lomax to Management Corporation of America, 1941-11-28
    - December 1941 (Box-folder 6/177)
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1941-12-02
      - Alan Lomax to Mary Jo Wallace, 1941-12-02
      - Alan Lomax to James Putnam, 1941-12-02
      - Eleanor Stierhem to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-03
        The American Magazine
      - Mary Jo Wallace to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-04
      - Alan Lomax to Captain Thomas Howard Carpenter, 1941-12-05
      - Alan Lomax to T.J. Brandon, 1941-12-05
      - Alan Lomax to Mary Jo Wallace, 1941-12-06
      - T.J. Brandon to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-08
      - Eleanor Stierhem to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-08
      - James Putnam to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-09
        Macmillan Company; enc.
      - Mary Jo Wallace to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-09
      - Bess Lomax to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-09
      - John T. Frederick to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-12
      - Alan Lomax to Eleanor Stierhem, 1941-12-12
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1941-12-12
      - Alan Lomax to T.J. Brandon, 1941-12-13
      - James "Iron Head" Baker to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-14
      - T.J. Brandon to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-15
        Brandon Films; enc.
      - Harold Spivacke to J.E. Bright, 1941-12-16
      - Eleanor Stierhem to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-17
      - Alan Lomax to Annabel Morris Buchanan, 1941-12-18
      - Eleanor Stierhem to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-22
      - Alan Lomax to Moses Smith, 1941-12-23
      - Alan Lomax to Fletcher Collins, Jr., 1941-12-23
      - Parker Wheatley to Alan Lomax, 1941-12-24
    - January 1942 (Box-folder 6/178)
      - Eleanor Stierhem to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-02
      - Alan Lomax to Josephine Schwartz, 1942-01-02
      - Francois-J. Brassard to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-07
        Universite Laval, Quebec
      - T.J. Brandon to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-08
      - Audio-Visual Services Corp. to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-08
        Audio-visual Services Corp
      - Fletcher Collins, Jr. to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-08
      - Moses Smith to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-09
      - Alan Lomax to John Hammond, 1942-01-10
      - Alan Lomax to Parker Wheatley, 1942-01-12
      - Alan Lomax to Eleanor Stierhem, 1942-01-12
      - Eleanor Stierhem to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-12
      - Parker Wheatley to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-13
      - Alan Lomax to Thomas H. Benton, 1942-01-13
      - John Hammond to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-15
      - Merritt H. Coleman to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-19
        Management Corporation of America
      - Alan Lomax to Parker Wheatley, 1942-01-20
      - T.J. Brandon to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-20
      - Thomas H. Benton to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-21
      - Alan Lomax to T.J. Brandon, 1942-01-22
      - Alan Lomax to Francois-J. Brassard, 1942-01-22
      - Alan Lomax to Audio-visual Services Corp, 1942-01-22
      - Harold L. Friedman to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-26
      - Alan Lomax to Hazel L. Muller, 1942-01-26
      - Merritt H. Coleman to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-26
      - Alan Lomax to Merritt H. Coleman, 1942-01-27
      - Alan Lomax to Thomas H. Benton, 1942-01-28
      - Merritt H. Coleman to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-29
      - J.A. Brown to Alan Lomax, 1942-01-31
    - February 1942 (Box-folder 6/179)
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-02-04
      - Harold L. Friedman to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-05
      - James Putnam to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-06
      - Alan Lomax to Merritt H. Coleman, 1942-02-07
      - Alan Lomax to James Putnam, 1942-02-09
      - Alan Lomax to Harold L. Friedman, 1942-02-09
      - Alan Lomax to Ethel Lomax Schumaker, 1942-02-12
      - Columbia Artists, Inc. to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-13
        Columbia, Artists, Inc.; contract
      - T.J. Brandon to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-16
      - Hon. Ed Gossett to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-16
        U.S. Congress
      - Jack Conroy to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-18
      - Alan Lomax to T.J. Brandon, 1942-02-19
      - Elmer G. Sulzer to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-20
      - Alan Lomax to Jack Conroy, 1942-02-21
      - Arthur Becker to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-21
        Star Record Co.
      - Frank Luther to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-24
        Decca Records
      - Hazel L. Muller to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-24
      - James Putnam to Alan Lomax, 1942-02-25
      - Alan Lomax to Elmer G. Sulzer, 1942-02-26
      - Alan Lomax to Frank Luther, 1942-02-26
      - Alan Lomax to Hazel L. Muller, 1942-02-26
      - Alan Lomax to Arthur Becker, 1942-02-27
    - March 1942 (Box-folder 6/180)
      - Alan Lomax to Verner W. Clapp, 1942-03-02
        Library of Congress Administrative Asst. to the Librarian
      - Ralph S. Boggs to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-02
      - Alan Lomax to Ralph S. Boggs, 1942-03-05
      - Frank Mlakar to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-05
        Common Ground
      - Ada to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-06
      - Alan Lomax to Davidson Taylor, 1942-03-06
      - Alan Lomax to Harold B. Armitage, 1942-03-09
      - Irene Carlisle to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-09
      - H.M. Bond to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-09
        Fort Valley (Georgia) State College
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-03-09
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-09
      - Alan Lomax to Columbia Broadcasting System, 1942-03-11
      - Davidson Taylor to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-11
      - Alan Lomax to Frank Mlakar, 1942-03-16
      - Frank Mlakar to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-16
      - Alan Lomax to H.M. Bond, 1942-03-16
      - Alan Lomax to Fletcher Collins, Jr., 1942-03-17
      - Fletcher Collins, Jr. to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-17
      - Alan Lomax to W.E. Claunch, 1942-03-18
        Performer release
      - Frank Mlakar to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-18
      - Alan Lomax to E.C. Ball, 1942-03-18
      - Alan Lomax to E.C. Ball, 1942-03-18
      - Alan Lomax to Smith Casey, 1942-03-19
      - Alan Lomax to James "Iron Head" Baker, 1942-03-20
      - Alan Lomax to James "Iron Head" Baker, 1942-03-20
      - Alan Lomax to Arthur Bell, 1942-03-20
      - H.M. Bond to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-21
      - Alice Whitmire to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-23
      - Alan Lomax to Irene Carlisle, 1942-03-23
      - Alan Lomax to Warden, Cummins State Farm, Gould, Arkansas, 1942-03-24
      - Alan Lomax to Sarah Harris, 1942-03-24
      - Frank Mlakar to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-25
      - Alan Lomax to Frank Mlakar, 1942-03-26
      - Frank Mlakar to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-28
      - Eleanor Stierhem to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-28
      - Carleton R. Brackett to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-28
      - Arthur Bell to Alan Lomax, 1942-03-30
    - April 1942 (Box-folder 6/181)
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942
      - Alan Lomax to M.P.O. Love, 1942-04-01
        Mississippi State Penitentiary at Parchman
      - Roger Butterfield to Alan Lomax, 1942-04-02
      - Alan Lomax to Frank Mlakar, 1942-04-02
      - Alan Lomax to Carleton R. Brackett, 1942-04-02
      - James Putnam to Alan Lomax, 1942-04-03
      - Benjamin A. Botkin to E.B. Steward, 1942-04-03
        Dallas Transfer and Terminal Warehouse Co.
      - Alan Lomax to Eleanor Stierhem, 1942-04-03
        The American Magazine; also draft from previous day
      - Alistair Cooke to Alan Lomax, 1942-04-07
      - I.S. Becker to Alan Lomax, 1942-04-07
      - Alan Lomax to U.S. Selective Service Board, 1942-04-08
        Address change
      - Alan Lomax to I.S. Becker, 1942-04-11
      - Alan Lomax to James "Iron Head" Baker, 1942-04-14
      - Alan Lomax to E.E. Moss, 1942-04-14
        Clemens State Farm, Brazoria, Texas
      - Alan Lomax to Elizabeth Austin, 1942-04-17
      - Alan Lomax to Elizabeth Austin, 1942-04-17
      - Alan Lomax to Fletcher Collins, Jr., 1942-04-18
      - Mary Donald Davis to Alan Lomax, 1942-04-20
      - Alex Petry to Alan Lomax, 1942-04-22
        Blue Network
      - Alan Lomax to Alex Petry, 1942-04-23
      - Mildred L. Batchelder to Alan Lomax, 1942-04-23
      - Carleton R. Brackett to Alan Lomax, 1942-04-23
      - Alan Lomax to Carriere Oakdale, 1942-04-24
      - Alan Lomax to Carriere Oakdale, 1942-04-24
      - Alan Lomax to Ricardo Archuleta, 1942-04-24
      - Alan Lomax to Cleveland Benoit, 1942-04-24
      - Alan Lomax to Joe Brown, 1942-04-24
      - Alan Lomax to Mary Gould Davis, 1942-04-25
      - Alan Lomax to Fletcher Collins, Jr., 1942-04-26
      - Alan Lomax to Richard Chase, 1942-04-28
      - Alan Lomax to Carleton R. Brackett, 1942-04-28
      - Alan Lomax to Robert P. Wetherald, 1942-04-29
      - Alan Lomax to E.E. Moss, 1942-04-30
      - Alan Lomax to Juan B. Rael, 1942-04-30
        University of Southern California
      - Thomas H. Benton to Alan Lomax, 1942-04
    - May 1942 (Box-folder 6/182)
      - Mary Gould Davis to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-01
      - Irene Carlisle to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-04
      - James "Iron Head" Baker to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-04
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-05
      - Richard Chase to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-05
      - Alan Lomax to Leo J. Nohe, 1942-05-07
        Postmaster, Jennings LA
      - Alan Lomax to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, 1942-05-08
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-05-09
      - Alan Lomax to D.D. Bazer, 1942-05-09
        Warden, Louisiana State Penitentiary, Angola
      - D.D. Bazer to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-10
      - Leo J. Nohe to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-11
      - Thomas W. Anderson to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-11
      - Ruby Pickens Tartt to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-12
      - Gladys Pitcher to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-13
        C.C. Birchard & Co.
      - Alan Lomax to postmaster, Lake Arthur, Louisiana, 1942-05-13
      - Alan Lomax to Joe Brown Washington, 1942-05-13
      - Alan Lomax to Joe Brown Washington, 1942-05-13
      - Alan Lomax to Ogdel Carrier, 1942-05-13
      - Alan Lomax to postmaster, Church Point, Louisiana, 1942-05-13
      - Alan Lomax to Thomas W. Anderson, 1942-05-13
      - Elizabeth Austin to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-13
      - Alan Lomax to Ruby Pickens Tartt, 1942-05-14
      - Alan Lomax to Irene Carlisle, 1942-05-15
      - Alan Lomax to Richard Chase, 1942-05-15
      - William W. Boddie to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-15
        Newsweek
      - Harvey J. Bouck to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-15
        Kalamazoo (Michigan) Teachers Lyceum
      - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-15
      - Alan Lomax to Gladys Pitcher, 1942-05-16
      - Alan Lomax to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, 1942-05-16
      - Alan Lomax to Smith Casey, 1942-05-18
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-21
        John A. Lomax 1942 recording trip
      - Alan Lomax to Rev. G.S. Rivers, 1942-05-21
      - Frances M. Foster to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-21
      - Alex Petry to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-25
      - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-25
      - Marc Blitzstein to Alan Lomax, 1942-05-25
        Our Singing Country review
      - Alan Lomax to Alex Petry, 1942-05-26
      - Alan Lomax to Harvey J. Bouck, 1942-05-27
      - David C. Mearns to Harold Spivacke, 1942-05-28
      - Harold Spivacke to David C. Mearns, 1942-05-30
    - June 1942 (Box-folder 6/183)
      - Jenny to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-14
      - S.K. Stevens to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-04
        Pennsylvania Historical Commission
      - Harold Spivacke to Verner W. Clapp, 1942-06-18
        Library of Congress Administrative Assistant to the Librarian
      - Edwin C. Kirlkand to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-19
        University of Tennessee
      - Alan Lomax to Library of Congress Music Division, 1942-06-23
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-06-25
      - Alan Lomax to Benjamin A. Botkin, 1942-06-25
      - Thomas to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-30
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-30
      - Alan Lomax to Leo J. Nohe, 1942-06-05
        Postmaster, Jennings Louisiana
      - Cleveland Benoit to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-08
      - Alan Lomax to Cleveland Benoit, 1942-06-11
      - Postmaster, Church Point, Louisiana to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-10
      - Alan Lomax to Harvey J. Bouck, 1942-06-20
      - Harvey J. Bouck to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-11
      - Alan Lomax to postmaster, Church Point, Louisiana, 1942-06-05
      - Alan Lomax to Lawrence W. Chappell, 1942-06-08
      - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-11
      - Alan Lomax to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, 1942-06-16
      - Alan Lomax to Samuel P. Bayard, 1942-06-20
        Harvard University
      - Alan Lomax to Lawrence W. Chappell, 1942-06-25
      - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-27
      - R.C. Archibald to Alan Lomax, 1942-06-29
        Brown University
    - July 1942 (Box-folder 6/184)
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-07-03
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-07-03
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-07-09
      - Harold Spivacke to David C. Mearns, 1942-07-09
        Drafts enclosed
      - Alan Lomax to Charles Seeger, 1942-07-09
      - Alan Lomax to Svatava Jakobson, 1942-07-09
      - Alan Lomax to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, 1942-07-09
      - Smith Casey to Alan Lomax, 1942-07-09
      - Alan Lomax to Samuel P. Bayard, 1942-07-09
      - Richard Chase to Alan Lomax, 1942-07-14
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-07-15
      - Harold Spivacke to David C. Mearns, 1942-07-16
      - Edward N. Waters to Alan Lomax, 1942-07-18
      - Alan Lomax to Smith Casey, 1942-07-20
      - Alan Lomax to Smith Casey, 1942-07-22
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-07-24
      - R.C. Archibald to Alan Lomax, 1942-07-25
      - H.L. Ridenour to Alan Lomax, 1942-07-27
        Baldwin-Wallace College
      - Alan Lomax to R.C. Archibald, 1942-07-27
      - R.C. Archibald to Alan Lomax, 1942-07-29
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-07
    - August 1942 (Box-folder 6/185)
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-08-01
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-08-07
      - Samuel P. Bayard to Alan Lomax, 1942-08-09
      - Edward N. Waters to Alan Lomax, 1942-08-10
      - Edward N. Waters to Gertie Colvin, 1942-08-13
      - Charles Seeger to Donald Goodchild, 1942-08-14
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-08-17
      - Fletcher Collins, Jr. to Alan Lomax, 1942-08-17
        Elon College, North Carolina; R.C. Archibald
      - S.T. Burns to Alan Lomax, 1942-08-24
      - Edward N. Waters to Richard Chase, 1942-08-25
      - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain to Alan Lomax, 1942-08-26
      - Svatava Jakobson to Alan Lomax, 1942-08-28
      - Alan Lomax to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, 1942-08-28
      - Edward N. Waters to Richard Chase, 1942-08-29
        Draft of 1942-08-25 letter
      - Gertie Colvin to Alan Lomax, 1942-08
    - September 1942 (Box-folder 6/186)
      - Alan Lomax to S.T. Burns, 1942-09-02
      - Alan Lomax to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, 1942-09-02
      - Alan Lomax to Joe Brown Washington, 1942-09-03
      - Alan Lomax to Elizabeth Austin, 1942-09-03
      - Alan Lomax to Ricardo Archuleta, 1942-09-03
      - Alan Lomax to Lonnie Odum, 1942-09-04
      - Richard Chase to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-07
      - Mary Waller Bonelli to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-07
      - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-08
      - Ralph S. Boggs to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-13
      - Alan Lomax to Svatava Jakobson, 1942-09-15
      - Ermine W. Voegelin to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-15
        American Folklore Society
      - Alan Lomax to Richard Chase, 1942-09-16
      - Alan Lomax to Vance Randolph, 1942-09-16
        Gertie Colvin
      - Alan Lomax to Mary Waller Bonelli, 1942-09-16
      - Alan Lomax to R.C. Archibald, 1942-09-16
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-09-18
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-09-18
      - Alan Lomax to Louis V. Chappell, 1942-09-19
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-21
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-21
      - Alan Lomax to Charles Berry, 1942-09-21
      - Richard Chase to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-22
      - Robert J. Blakely to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-22
        Office of War Information
      - Earl Robinson to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-22
      - Alan Lomax to Ralph S. Boggs, 1942-09-23
      - Alan Lomax to Arthur Posnansky, 1942-09-23
      - Vance Randolph to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-24
      - Mabel Christie to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-25
      - Alan Lomax to William C. Haygood, 1942-09-26
        Julius Rosenwald Fund
      - Jean Slater Appel to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-26
        American Guild of Organists
      - Lawrence W. Chappell to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-27
      - Alan Lomax to Fletcher Collins, Jr., 1942-09-28
      - Alan Lomax to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, 1942-09-28
      - E.C. Ball to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-28
      - Alan Lomax to Mabel Christie, 1942-09-29
      - Arthur L. Campa to Alan Lomax, 1942-09-29
        University of New Mexico
      - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain to Alan Lomax, 1942-09
    - October 1942 (Box-folder 6/187)
      - William C. Haygood to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-02
      - Willis Lawrence James to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-02
        Spelman College
      - S.T. Burns to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-02
      - John N. Vincent to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-03
        Western Kentucky State Teachers College
      - Alan Lomax to Susan S. Prink, 1942-10-03
      - Alice and Ross Whitmore to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-03
      - William H. Pipes to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-07
      - Donald Goodchild to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-08
      - Donald Goodchild to George Herzog, 1942-10-08
      - Alan Lomax to E.C. Ball, 1942-10-08
      - Alan Lomax to various booksellers, 1942-10-09
      - Alan Lomax to Archibald MacLeish, 1942-10-09
        Transfer to Office of War Information
      - Alan Lomax to Homer P. Rainey, 1942-10-09
      - Alan Lomax to S.T. Burns, 1942-10-09
      - Alan Lomax to Donald Goodchild, 1942-10-10
      - Alan Lomax to Charles Seeger, 1942-10-10
        Pan-American Union
      - Mrs. L.L. McDowell to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-11
      - Ralph S. Boggs to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-13
      - Svatava Jakobson to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-19
      - Homer P. Rainey to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-26
      - Alan Lomax to Lawrence W. Chappell, 1942-10-27
      - Alan Lomax to John, 1942-10-27
      - Alan Lomax to Helen Creighton, 1942-10-27
      - Alan Lomax to Willis Lawrence James, 1942-10-27
      - Alan Lomax to William C. Haygood, 1942-10-27
      - Alan Lomax to Homer P. Rainey, 1942-10-27
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-27
      - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-28
      - J.A. Moore to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-29
      - Alan Lomax to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, 1942-10-30
      - Alan Lomax to William H. Pipes, 1942-10-30
      - Lawrence W. Chappell to Alan Lomax, 1942-10-30
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1942-10-30
        Suzanne Sylvain Comhaire
    - November 1942 (Box-folder 6/188)
      - Homer P. Rainey to Alan Lomax, 1942-11-02
      - Alan Lomax to Mody C. Boatright, 1942-11-02
        Texas Folk-Lore Society
      - Alan Lomax to Homer P. Rainey, 1942-11-02
      - Alan Lomax to Lyman Bryson, 1942-11-03
      - Benjamin A. Botkin to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, 1942-11-03
      - William C. Haygood to Alan Lomax, 1942-11-05
      - Alan Lomax to Benjamin A. Botkin, 1942-11-06
        No addressee
      - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain to Alan Lomax, 1942-11-08
      - Mody C. Boatright to Alan Lomax, 1942-11-10
      - Joanna C. Colcord to Alan Lomax, 1942-11-11
      - Alan Lomax to William H. Pipes, 1942-11-12
      - Willis Lawrence James to Alan Lomax, 1942-11-12
      - Alan Lomax to Benjamin A. Botkin, 1942-11-13
      - Willis Lawrence James to Alan Lomax, 1942-11-16
        Spelman College; enc.
      - Benjamin A. Botkin to Fletcher Collins, Jr., 1942-11-16
      - Homer P. Rainey to Alan Lomax, 1942-11-17
      - Harold Spivacke to Lyman Bryson, 1942-11-21
    - December 1942 (Box-folder 6/189)
      - Vance Randolph to Alan Lomax, 1942-12-05
      - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain to Alan Lomax, 1942-12-05
      - Jim to Alan Lomax, 1942-12-06
        Book proposal
      - Willis Lawrence James to Alan Lomax, 1942-12-08
      - Alan Lomax to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, 1942-12-09
      - Elizabeth Austin to Alan Lomax, 1942-12-09
      - Alan Lomax to Mody C. Boatright, 1942-12-10
      - Ruby Pickens Tartt to Alan Lomax, 1942-12-10
      - Benjamin A. Botkin to Ruby Pickens Tartt, 1942-12-16
      - Alan Lomax to Theodore M. Finney, 1942-12-22
      - Alan Lomax to James Allen, 1942-12-22
      - Alan Lomax to Herbert Hunsaker, 1942-12-22
      - James Allen to Alan Lomax, 1942-12-28
      - Alan Lomax to various, 1942-12
        Notes
    - January-April 1943 (Box-folder 7/190)
      - Henry Allen Moe to Alan Lomax, 1943-01-07
        John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
      - Alan Lomax to John N. Vincent, 1943-01-09
      - Alan Lomax to Vance Randolph, 1943-01-09
      - Alan Lomax to William H. Pipes, 1943-01-09
      - Alan Lomax to Willis Lawrence James, 1943-01-09
      - William H. Pipes to Alan Lomax, 1943-01-12
      - John N. Vincent to Alan Lomax, 1943-01-20
      - Alan Lomax to William H. Pipes, 1943-01-23
      - Alan Lomax to Joseph A. Brandt, 1943-02-06
      - Alan Lomax to Willis Lawrence James, 1943-02-06
      - Alan Lomax to William C. Haygood, 1943-02-08
      - William C. Haygood to Alan Lomax, 1943-02-11
      - Alan Lomax to William C. Haygood, 1943-02-13
      - Alan Lomax to Willis Lawrence James, 1943-02-13
      - Alan Lomax to Woody Guthrie, 1943-02-13
      - Alan Lomax to William H. Pipes, 1943-02-13
      - Alan Lomax to Willis Lawrence James, 1943-03-03